Guide to the Free to Dance Records, 1987-2004
American Dance Festival Archives Durham, N.C., USA
- Production Records, 1994-2001 and undated (Box 5)
  - Pre-Production Files, 1994-2001 and undated, 6.25 linear feet
    - Secondary Sources Research Files, 3.5 linear feet
      - Williams, Lavinia, 1954
      - Winfield, Hemsley, 1931-1934
      - Women, Choreography: Goler, Veta. Dancing Herself: Choreography, Autobiography, and the Expression of the Black Woman Self in the Work of Dianne McIntyre, Blondell Cummings, and Jawole Willa Jo Zollar, 1994
      - World War II, 1935-1998 (2 folders)
    - Treatments, Outlines, Scripts, 1995-1998 and undated, 4 folders
      - Show 1, 1998-1999
      - Show 2, 1998-1999
      - Show 3, 1998-1999
      - Series, 1995 and undated
  - Production Files, 1994-2001 and undated, 7.25 linear feet
    Contains records created during the production of original footage shot specifically for Free to Dance and the gathering of archival resources used in the completed program.
    - Film Shoot Production Files, 1994-2000, 2 linear feet
      Includes the production records from the filming of interviews and dances shot specifically for inclusion in Free to Dance, including production itineraries, travel arrangements, camera and sound reports, information on film and lighting equipment, receipts, budgets, invoices, and correspondence with film crews and interviewees.
      Arranged chronologically by the date of each film shoot.
      - Eugene Von Grona, Dec. 16, 1994
      - Donald McKayle, Talley Beatty, Feb. 6, 1995
      - Trinidad (Molly Ayhe, Boscoe Holder, Raymond Watt), Mar. 12-18, 1998 (4 folders)
      - East St. Louis (Katherine Dunham) and Chicago (Tommy Gomez), Apr. 24-28, 1998 (3 folders)
      - Joe Nash, May 29, June 8, 1998
      - American Dance Festival (Dayton Contemporary Dance Company and Cleo Parker Robinson Dance Ensemble), June 12-16, 1998 (13 folders)
      - Atlanta (Richard Long and Sylvius Moore), July 7-8, 1998
      - Carmencita Romero and Charles Queenan, July 17, 1998
      - Philadelphia (Philadanco, Brenda Dixon Gottschild), July 20-24, 1998 (5 folders)
      - Babatunde Olatunji and Merle Derby, Aug. 6, 1998 (3 folders)
      - Dayton, OH (Donald McKayle and Ronald K. Brown with Dayton Contemporary Dance Company), Aug. 29-Sept. 2, 1998 (3 folders)
      - Vanoye Aikens, Joe Nash, Katrina Hazard Donald, Eleo Pomare, Sept. 14-15, 1998 (3 folders) (Box 11)
      - Merle Derby and Dale Wasserman, Sept. 23, 1998 (2 folders)
      - Hampton, VA (Nina Butts, Elaine Cook, Armistead Tull, Mary Barbee Boone Pleasant), Oct. 23-27, 1998 (3 folders)
      - Carmen de Lavallade, Evelyn Pilcher, Muriel Manings, Miki Borde, Dorene Richardson, Nov. 14-15, 1998 (2 folders)
      - Jackie Goldman, Cristyne Lawson, Clive Thompson, Beryl Murray Campbel, Dec. 2-3, 1998 (3 folders)
      - Bill T. Jones and Zita Allen, Dec. 9, 1998 (2 folders)
      - Ruth Beckford, Peter Wood, Jean Leon Destine, Chief Bey, Christine Gray, Dean Sheldon, Leon Bibb, Dec. 16-19, 1998 (3 folders)
      - S'thembile West and James Haskins, Jan. 8, 1999
      - Durham, NC (Richard Powell, Chuck Davis), Jan. 16, 1999
      - Lynne Conner, Jan. 18, 1999
      - Dayton, OH (Dayton Contemporary Dance Company: Sheri Williams and Gary Harris), Feb. 5-6, 1999 (3 folders)
      - Donald McKayle and Beryl Murray Campbell, Mar. 4, 1999
      - Edna Guy/Ruth St. Denis Recreations, Mar. 8-11, 21, 1999 (3 folders)
      - Bill T. Jones and Estella Jones, Abdel Salaam, Apr. 6, 1999
      - Forces of Nature (Abdel Salaam), Apr. 12-13, 1999
      - Halifu Osumare, Gus Solomons, Jr., Apr. 24, 1999
      - American Dance Festival (Bill T. Jones, African American Dance Ensemble, Strange Fruit) June 9-10, 1999 (9 folders)
      - Hope Clarke, Julie Belafonte, Charles Queenan, July 29, 1999
      - Jawole Willa Jo Zollar, Ronald K. Brown, Rennie Harris, Aug. 17, 1999
      - Buster Brown, Trisha Brown, Judith Jamison, Eloise Hill Anderson, Katherine Dunham, Aug. 25-26, 1999
      - Geoffrey Holder, Dianne Walker, Garth Fagan, Roslynde LeBlanc, Oct. 12, 1999
      - Jawole Willa Jo Zollar, Bill T. Jones, Zita Allen, Paul Jefferson, Julia Foulkes, Dec. 14, 1999
      - John Perpener, Mar. 16, 2000
      - Edna Guy/Ruth St. Denis Recreations Voice-over, June 14, 2000
    - Film, Tape, and Sound Rolls, 1998-2000 and undated, 3 folders
      - Delivery Receipts, 1998-2000
      - Logs, 1998 and undated
      - Stock, 1998-2000
    - Vendors, 1994-2000, 3 folders
      - Cinepost, 1998
      - DuArt, 1994-1995, 1998-2000
      - WRS Motion Picture and Video Laboratories, 1998-1999
    - Repository Files, 1994-2001, 4.75 linear feet (Box 12)
      Contains correspondence, licensing negotiations, and other materials regarding film, video, sound recordings, photographs, and other documents considered for inclusion in Free to Dance. These materials were compiled by research staff Jenna Lambie, Prudence Arndt, Lewanne Jones, and, occasionally, interns Jada Shapiro and Rachelle Michaud. Several freelance researchers were also employed, two working in Washington, DC, and two in Europe.
      Arranged alphabetically by archival repository, stock house, library, or individual owner.
      - Eugene Von Grona, Dec. 16, 1994
      - A: Alabama Archives-Ayers Publishing, 1998-2000
      - Alvin Ailey American Dance Theater, 1997-2000 (2 folders)
      - ABC News Video Source, 1999-2000
      - American Dance Asylum (Bill T. Jones), 2000
      - American Dance Festival Archives Moving Images Inventories, 1989-1998 (2 folders)
      - American Museum of Natural History, 1998
      - ARC Video: Eye on Dance and the Arts Series Catalog, circa 1980-1989
      - Associated Press/Wide World Photos (Katherine Dunham, Lynchings), 1999
      - Association for Cultural Equity, 1998, 2000
      - Atkin, Jonathon (photographer), 1999
      - B: Bader-British Pathe, 1998-1999
      - Barzel, Ann (Katherine Dunham), 1998-2000
      - British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC) (Alvin Ailey), 1998-2000
      - Bennington Museum (Pageants), 1998
      - Berryman-Johnson, Sherrill (Pearl Primus), 1999
      - Bill T. Jones/Arnie Zane Dance Company, 1999
      - Black Patti Research Project, 1998
      - Bonner, Norman and Johanna McCully-Bonner (Edna Guy), 2000
      - Boston Public Library, 1998
      - Brooklyn Academy of Music, 2000
      - Brown University, John Hay Library: William Chauncey Langdon Collection (Pageantry), 1998-1999
      - Bundesachiv (Federal Archives of Germany) (Mary Wigman), 1999
      - Burns, Stanley/Burns Collection: Lynching Stills, 1999
      - C: Carol Publishing Agency-Cuyjet, 1998-2001
      - California Institute of the Arts (Cal Arts) (Gus Solomons, Jr.), 1999
      - Canadian Broadcasting Corporation (CBC) (Donald McKayle), 1998-2000
      - Caribbean Cultural Center (Katherine Dunham Films), 1999-2000
      - Caribbean Cultural Center: Caribe Magazine 7:1-2, 1982
      - CBS News Archives (Alvin Ailey), 1998-2000
      - Chertok Associates, Inc., Jazz on Film, Chertok Archives, 1998-2000
      - Chicago Historical Society (Katherine Dunham, Chicago), 1998
      - Cinemateque de la Dance (Katherine Dunham), 1998 (2 folders)
      - Cine Search, 1998
      - Columbia University, 1998, 2000
      - Congress on Research in Dance Conference: Proposal by John O. Perpener III, 1995
      - Cornell University, Kheel Center, International Ladies' Garments Workers' Union Records (Pins and Needles),1998
      - Creative Arts Television Archive (Lester Horton), 1998-2000
      - D: Dance Magazine-Duke University Press, 1995, 1998, 1999
      - Dance Films Association (Helen Tamiris), 1997, 2000
      - Danish Broadcasting Corporation, 1995, 1998-2000
      - Deutsche Wochenschau Gmbh (Katherine Dunham), 1998-1999
      - Dinizulu Cultural Archives, 1999
      - E: Eiko and Koma-Encyclopedia Britannica, 1998-1999
      - Esquire, 2000
      - F: Facets-Frameline Distribution, 1995-1999
      - F.I.L.M. Archives, 1999
      - Film & Video Stock Shots, 2000
      - Footage: The Worldwide Movie Image Sourcebook, 1998
      - G: George Mason University-GRM Associates, 1998-2000
      - Glazer, Gabby (Eugene Von Grona), 1999
      - Gould, Michael (Katherine Dunham), 2000
      - H: Hansen-Hunter College, 1998-2000
      - Hampton University Archives. 1998-1999 (2 folders)
      - Helman, Lawrence and Mark Heustis, 1999-2000
      - Hinton, James, 1999-2000
      - Historic Films, 1998-2000
      - Holman, Michael (Break Dancing), 1999
      - Hot Shots/Cool Cuts, 1998-2000
      - Huntley Film Archives (Harlem, New York City Nightclubs), 1998
      - Hurston, Zora Neale, Estate, 1998, 2000
      - I: Image Back-Indiana University, 1998-2000
      - Illuminations Television (Bill T. Jones/Arnie Zane Dance Co.), 2000
      - Image Bank, Petrified Films Collection, 2000
      - Institut National de l'Audiovisuel (INA) (Katherine Dunham), 1999-2000 (2 folders)
      - ITN Archive, Reuters Television, 1999-2000
      - Jacob's Pillow, 1996, 1999-2000 (Box 13)
      - Jim Dennis Photography (Garth Fagan), 1998-2000
      - John E. Allen. Inc. (JEA), 1998-2000
      - Journal and Guide (Katherine Dunham), 2000
      - K: Kentucky Railway Museum-Kroll Productions, 1999-2000
      - Katherine Dunham Center, 1998-2000
      - Kennedy, Stetson (Lynchings, Jim Crow, Civil Rights), 1999
      - Kindem, Gorham, 2000
      - Kitchen Center for Video, Music, Dance, Performance, Film and Literature, 1999-2000
      - Kultur International Films Ltd. (Alvin Ailey), 1999
      - L: Laursen-Louise-Victor Gollancz, 1998-2001
      - Lerner, Leah (Pearl Primus at Camp Wo Chi Ca), 1999
      - Library of Congress, 1998-2000 (6 folders)
      - List of Resources, Tape Logs, 1998
      - Lobster Films, 1998
      - M: Magnum Photos-Movin' Spirits Dance Theater, 1998-2000
      - MacDonald and Associates (Historical Stock Footage), 1998, 2000
      - Mangolte, Babette(Water Motor, Trisha Brown), 2000
      - Mahoney, Billie (Alvin Ailey), 1998, 2000
      - Mariners' Museum (Sailing and Boats), 1998
      - Michael Blackwood Productions, 1999-2000
      - Missouri Historical Society (Katherine Dunham Photograph Collection), 1998-2000
      - Moore, Barbara, 1999
      - Morgan, Lloyd, Barbara Morgan Photograph Collections, 1998
      - Muller, Nancy (Pearl Primus), 1998-2000
      - Municipal Archives of the City of New York (Views of Manhattan, Federal Writers Project), undated
      - Museum of the City of New York (Ruth St. Denis, Denishawn), 1999-2000
      - Museum of Modern Art, Department of Film and Video, 1998
      - Museum of Television and Radio,1998
      - N: Nash-New York University, 1998-2000
      - Nash, Joe, 2000
      - National Archives and Records Administration (NARA), 1998-2000 (6 folders)
      - NBC News Archives, 1998-1999
      - Newberry Library (Katherine Dunham), 1999-2000
      - New Dance Group Arts Center, 1998
      - News Hour with Jim Lehrer, MacNeil-Lehrer Productions (Aids in the Arts, Bill T. Jones, Arnie Zane), 2000
      - New York Public Library, Billy Rose Theatre Collection (Eugene Von Grona, Pearl Primus), 1998
      - New York Public Library Catalog Search Results, 1998-2000 (2 folders)
      - New York Public Library, Dance Collection (Alvin Ailey), 1999-2000
      - New York Public Library, Dance Collection (Talley Beatty), 2000
      - New York Public Library, Dance Collection (Katherine Dunham), 1998, 2000
      - New York Public Library, Dance Collection (Edna Guy, Ruth St. Denis), 2000
      - New York Public Library, Dance Collection Footage, 1993 (4 folders)
      - New York Public Library, Dance Collection (Judson Dance Theater), 1999 (Box 14)
      - New York Public Library, Dance Collection Reference Requests, 1998-2000 (2 folders)
      - New York Public Library, Dance Collection, Schomburg Center for Research in Black Culture (5 folders)
      - New York Times (Judith Jameson, Katherine Dunham), 2000
      - Northwestern University (Melville Herskovits, Katherine Dunham), 1999
      - NOS (Katherine Dunham, Alvin Ailey), 1999-2000 (2 folders)
      - Odyssey Productions (Roots of Tap on a North Carolina Back Porch), 2000
      - P: PBS-Princeton Book Company, 1999-2000
      - Pathe Television, 1998-2000
      - Penn, Robert E.(Ronald K. Brown/EVIDENCE), 2000
      - Pennebaker Hegedus Films, 1999-2000
      - Phoenix/BFA/Coronet Educational Media, 1998
      - Pomare, Eleo, 1999
      - Producers Library Service, 1998, 2000
      - R: Ramos-Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive, 1998-2000
      - Riverside Church Archives (Von Grona Dance Company), 1999
      - RM Associates, (Alvin Ailey American Dance Theater), 1999-2000
      - Rounder Records, Alan Lomax Collection Catalog of Music Recordings, 1998
      - Ruth Page Foundation (Katherine Dunham), 1998
      - S: Schiavone-SUNY Brockport, 1998-2000
      - Scorer Productions (Last Supper at Uncle Tom's Cabin, Bill T. Jones and Arnie Zane), 1999-2000
      - Sears, Roebuck and Co. Archives (Julius Rosenwald), 1999
      - Second Line Search, 1999-2000
      - Sherman Grinberg Film Library, 1998-1999
      - Smith, Marvin and Morgan Smith Brothers Collection, 1998-2000
      - Smithsonian Institution, Ernie Smith Jazz Film Collection, 1998
      - Smithsonian Institution, Human Studies Film Archive, 2000
      - Solomons, Gus, Jr., 1999
      - Southern Illinois University (Katherine Dunham Papers), 1998-2000
      - Summers, Elaine (Judson Dance Theater, Janet Collins), 1999
      - Sveringes Television (Katherine Dunham), 1997-1999 (2 folders)
      - T: Tatge/Lasseur Productions-Tschinke, 1999-2000
      - Thirteen WNET, 1998-2000 (3 folders)
      - Trisha Brown Dance Company, 2000
      - Twentieth Century Fox Film Corp., 1998, 2000
      - Twin Cities Public Television, KCTA-TV, 1999-2000
      - Twin Palms Publishers, 2000
      - U: United Nations-Urban Bush Women, 1998-2001
      - University of California, Berkeley, Bancroft Library (Denishawn Dancers), 1999
      - University of California Los Angeles Film and Television Archive, 1998-1999
      - University of California Irvine Libraries (Infinite Journey: Donald McKayle's Life in Dance Exhibit), 1999
      - University of Florida, Belknap Collection for the Performing Arts, 1998, 2000
      - University of Georgia, Peabody Collection, 1998
      - University of Mississippi, Southern Media Archive, 1998
      - University of Rochester, Dance Film Archive (Ruth St. Denis, Denishawn), 1998-2000
      - University of South Carolina, 1998
      - V: VAGA-Voice Arts Productions, 1998-2000
      - Video D Studios (Urban Bush Women), 2000
      - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts (Urban Bush Women), 2000
      - Warner Bros. (Carnival of Rhythm)1998-2000
      - Wesleyan University, Wesleyan Cinema Archives, 1998
      - WGBH,1999-2000 (2 folders)
      - Window to the World Communications, WTTW, 1998, 2000 (Box 15)
      - Wisconsin Center for Film and Theatre Research, 1998
      - Woody Guthrie Foundation (New Dance Group), 1998
      - WORK Rochester (Garth Fagan, The Lion King), 1999
      - WPA Film Library, MPI Media Group, 1998-2000 (2 folders)
      - Yale University Library, 1999-2000
    - Production Database Printouts, 1 linear foot
      Printouts of Archival Producer Jenna Lambie's databases for photographs, footage, and repository contact information.
  - Post-Production Files, 1994-2001 and undated, 1.75 linear feet
    Contains records created during editing and other post-production activities.
    - Correspondence, 1998-2001, 4 folders
      - Closed captioning, 2000
      - Consultants, 2000
      - Filler, 2000-2001
      - Project Management, Editing, Voice-over, 1998-2000
    - Credits, 1999-2001, 8 folders (Box 16)
      - Correspondence, 1999-2001
      - Drafts, 2000 (5 folders)
      - Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, 2000
      - Lower Thirds, 2000
    - Deliverables, 1999-2001, 2 folders
      - Deliverables, 1999-2001
      - Correspondence: Katherine Dunham loaned materials, 2000
    - Documentation, 1998-2000 and undated, 7 folders
      - Footage: Reference Tape Log, 1998
      - Music, 2000
      - Visual Arts, undated
      - Visual Arts, Show 1, undated
      - Visual Arts, Show 2, undated
      - Visual Arts, Show 3, undated
      - Visual Arts: Photograph and Text Reproductions, undated (Box OS1)
    - Editing, 1998-2000 and undated, 5 folders (Box 16)
      - Correspondence, 1998-1999
      - Sound, Music, 2000
      - Visible Time Code Logs: Show 1, undated
      - Visible Time Code Logs: Show 2, undated
      - Visible Time Code Logs: Show 3, undated
    - Oral History Interview Transcripts, 1994-1999, 70 folders
      Oral histories of dancers, choreographers, and scholars were recorded to film, video, and audiotape. Transcripts were made to assist in editing.
      Arranged alphabetically. Dates on the folders refer to dates that the interviews took place.
      - Aikens, Vanoye, Sept. 14, 1998
      - Ahye, Molly, Mar. 13, 1998
      - Allen, Zita, Dec. 9, 1998
      - Anderson, Eloise Hill, Aug. 26, 1999
      - Beatty, Talley, Feb. 6, 1995
      - Beckford, Ruth, Dec. 16, 1998
      - Belafonte, Julie, July 29, 1999
      - Bibb, Leon, Dec. 19, 1998
      - Borde, Miki, Nov. 15, 1998
      - Brown, Buster, Aug. 25, 1999
      - Brown, Ronald K., Aug. 17, 1999
      - Brown, Ronald K., and Donald McKayle, Aug. 17, 1999
      - Brown, Trisha, Aug. 25, 1999
      - Butts, Nina, Oct. 26, 1998
      - Chief Bey, Dec. 17, 1998
      - Christa, Gabri, Mar. 1999
      - Clarke, Hope, July, 29, 1999
      - Conner, Lynne, Jan. 18, 1999
      - Cook, Elaine, Oct. 24, 1998
      - Davis, Chuck, Jan. 16, 1999
      - de Lavallade, Carmen, Nov. 14, 1998
      - Derby, Merle, Sept. 23, 1998
      - Destine, Jean Leon, Dec. 17, 1998
      - Donald, Katrina Hazzard, Sept. 14, 1998
      - Dunham, Katherine, Apr. 22-23, 1998, Aug. 26, 1999
      - Fagan, Garth, Oct. 12, 1999
      - Foulkes, Julia, Dec. 14, 1999
      - Goldman, Jackie, Dec. 2, 1998
      - Gottschild, Brenda Dixon, July 23, 1998
      - Gray, Christine, Dec. 18, 1998
      - Harris, Gary, Feb. 5, 1999
      - Harris, Rennie, Aug. 7, 1999
      - Haskins, James, Jan. 8, 1999
      - Heard, Marcia, Jan. 18, 1999
      - Holder, Boscoe, Mar. 14, 1998
      - Holder, Geoffrey, Oct. 12, 1999
      - Jamison, Judith, Aug. 25, 1999
      - Jefferson, Paul, Dec. 14, 1999
      - Jones, Bill T., Dec. 9, 1998, Dec. 14, 1999
      - Lawson, Christine, Dec. 2, 1998
      - LeBlanc, Rosalynde, Oct. 22, 1999
      - Long, Richard, July 8, 1998
      - McKayle, Donald, Feb. 6, 1995, Mar. 1999
      - Manings, Muriel, Nov. 14, 1998
      - Moore, Sylvius, July 8, 1998
      - Nash, Joe, June 9, 1998, Sept. 14, 1998 (Box 17)
      - Nettleford, Rex, Jan. 18, 1999
      - Nicks, Walter, Dec. 18, 1998
      - Osumare, Halifu, Apr. 24, 1999
      - Pilcher, Evelyn, Nov. 14, 1998
      - Pleasant, May, Oct. 24, 1998
      - Pomare, Eleo, Sept. 15, 1998
      - Queenan, Charles, July, 17, 1998
      - Richardson, Dorene, Nov. 15, 1998
      - Robinson, Cleo Parker, Sept.1, 1998
      - Romero, Carmencita, July 17, 1998
      - Salaam, Abdel, Apr. 13, 1999
      - Sheldon, Dean, Dec. 19, 1998
      - Solomonoff, Henry, Dec. 16, 1994
      - Solomons, Gus, Apr. 24, 1999
      - Thomas, Ted, Mar. 1999
      - Thompson, Clive, Dec. 3, 1998
      - Von Grona, Eugene, Dec. 16, 1994
      - Walker, Dianne, Oct.12, 1999
      - Washington, Donald, Dec. 16, 1995
      - Wasserman, Dale, Sept. 23, 1998
      - Watt, Raymond, Mar. 18, 1998
      - West, S'thembile, Jan. 8, 1999
      - Williams, Sheri, Feb. 5, 1999
      - Wood, Peter, Dec. 16, 1998
      - Zollar, Jawole Willa Jo, Dec. 14, 1999, Aug. 17, 1999
    - Oral History Interview Selects, 9 folders
      The selection of interviews by the producers for inclusion in the final cut resulted in interview selects.
      Arranged alphabetically.
      - Aikens-Ahye
      - Beatty-Butts
      - Christa-Dunham
      - Fagan-Heard
      - Jamison-Long
      - Manings-Osumare
      - Perpener-Romero
      - Salaam-Zollar
      - Oral History
- Promotion and Marketing Records, 1998-2001 and undated, 2 linear feet (Box 17)
  Arranged into two subseries: Press and Publicity and Marketing.
  - Press and Publicity, 2000-2001, 7 folders
    - Air Dates, Thirteen WNET, 2001
    - Clippings, 2000-2001
    - Fact Sheets, 2000-2001
    - Press Kits, 2000-2001
    - Press Releases, 2000-2001
    - Printed Materials, 2000-2001
    - Printed Materials Correspondence, 2000-2001
    - Posters (Box OS1)
  - Marketing, 1998-2001, 13 folders (Box 17)
    - Book: Free to Dance, Correspondence, 2000
    - Book: Free to Dance, Manuscript, 2000 (3 folders)
    - Book: Free to Dance, Manuscript, 2000 (Box OS1)
    - Book: Free to Dance, 16" x 18" loose-leaf mock-up, 2000
    - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 17)
    - Film Festivals and Screenings, 2000-2001
    - Promotional Video for Dayton Contemporary Dance Company, 1998-1999
    - Tribute to Katherine Dunham, 2000
    - Website, 2000-2001 (3 folders)
- Photographic Materials, 1995-2001 and undated, 2.25 linear feet (Box 18)
  Prints, slides, negatives, and contact sheets from a variety of sources, used or created during the production of Free to Dance.
  Arranged into three subseries: Production Photographs, Publicity Photographs, and Production Snapshots.
  - Production Photographs, 1995-2000
    - Prints, 1997-2000, 10 folders
      - Ailey, Alvin, Janet Collins, Ulysses Dove, Edna Guy
      - Dance Schools, Lynching
      - Dunham, Katherine (2 folders)
      - Free to Dance Office, circa 1997-2000
      - Von Grona, Eugene, and Leni Bouvier, Von Grona Dance Company
      - Hampton Institute
      - Negro Ocean Playground, Helmsley Winfield Dance Group, Jazz Musicians Count Basie, Hal Blaine, and Joe Williams
      - "School", January 16-17, 1998
      - Solomons, Gus, Jr.
    - Negatives and Contact Sheets, 1995-1998, 14 folders
      - Cleo Parker Robinson Dance Ensemble, undated
      - Dayton Contemporary Dance Company, Children of the Passage, 1995
      - Dayton Contemporary Dance Company, Children of the Passage, Feb. 10, 1998
      - Dayton Contemporary Dance Company, Children of the Passage, Mourner's Bench, Rainbow 'Round My Shoulder, undated
      - Dayton Contemporary Dance Company, Children of the Passage Rehearsal, Aug. 19- Sept. 2, 1998
      - Dayton Contemporary Dance Company, Mourner's Bench, undated
      - Dunham, Katherine, Choros, undated
      - G441, G443, undated
      - Guy, Edna, and Ruth St. Denis Letters, undated
      - Lacy, Madison Davis, Snapshots, undated
      - Lacy, Madison Davis, Snapshots, Rainbow 'Round My Shoulder, undated
      - Trinidad, Feb. 10, 1998
      - Unidentified, Mar. 15, 1998
      - Unidentified, undated
  - Publicity Photographs, 1998 and undated
    - Prints, 1998 and undated, 11 folders
      - Alvin Ailey American Dance Theatre, Revelations
      - Bill T. Jones/Arnie Zane Dance Company, Etude
      - Bill T. Jones/Arnie Zane Dance Company, Last Night on Earth
      - Davis, Chuck, 1998
      - Dayton Contemporary Dance Company, Children of the Passage, Mourner's Bench, Awassa Astrige/Ostrich
      - Dunham, Katherine
      - Fagan, Garth
      - Philadanco, Strange Fruit
      - Primus, Pearl
      - Ronald K. Brown/EVIDENCE, Angelitos Negros, Dirt Road
      - Urban Bush Women
    - Slides, undated, 7 folders
      - African American Dance Ensemble
      - Alvin Ailey American Dance Theater
      - Cleo Parker Robinson Dance Ensemble
      - Dayton Contemporary Dance Ensemble
      - Free to Dance Logos
      - Jones, Bill T.
      - Philadanco
  - Production Snapshots: Prints and Negatives, 1998-1999, 1 linear foot, 62 envelopes (Box 19)